Finding Aid for the Josiah Royce Memorial Collection, 1875-1936
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
- Writings about Royce, and Reviews of his Books
  - Portrait of Josiah Royce, the Philosopher. In the Outlook (vol.122, no.9).July 2, 1916., Chapman, John Jay; p.4. (Box 16)
  - Professor Josiah Royce. In the Harvard Alumni Bulletin (vol.19, no.1).September 28, 1916., Hocking, William Ernest; p.4. (Box 16)
  - Royce's Philosophy of Religion. In Bibliotheca Sacra (vol.71, no.282).April 1914., Carr, Edwin S.; p.283. (Box 16)
  - La philosophie morale de Josiah Royce; essai sur l'idéalisme social aux Etats-Unis d'Amerique. Paris: Librairie Félix Alcan.1927., Aronson, Moses Judah (Box 16)
  - A Bibliography of the Unpublished Writings of Josiah Royce. In the Philosophical Review (vol.26, no.5).September 1917., p.578. (Box 16)
  - The Doctrine of Evolution and the Conception of God. In the American Journal of Theology (vol.19, no.4).October 1915., Kawaguchi, Ukichi; p.556. (Box 16)
  - Professor Royce and the Problem of Christianity. In the North American Review (vol.198, no.5).November 1913., Driscoll, John T.; p.640. (Box 16)
  - America's Duty Today, from the Point of View of a Hospital Doctor. In the Outlook (vol.115, no.14).April 4, 1917., Cabot, Richard C.; p.606. (Box 16)
  - The Contribution of Professor Royce to Christian Thought. In the Harvard Theological Review (vol.8, no.2).April 1915., Buckham, John Wright; p.219. 2 copies. (Box 16)
  - Review of The World and the Individual. In the Harvard Graduates' Magazine (vol.8, no.31).March 1900., Cabot, Richard C.; p.317. (Box 16)
  - Review of William James and other Essays on the Philosophy of Life. In the International Journal of Ethics (vol.22, no.3).April 1912., p.354. (Box 16)
  - Josiah Royces Versuch einer Synthese von Pragmatismus und Objektivität. Jena, Universitäts-Buchdrukerei G. Neuenhahn.1926., Rothman, Walter (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce, 1855-1916. Reprinted from the Proceedings of the British Academy (vol.7)., Sorley, W.R. (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce. In the Outlook (vol.114, no.4).September 27, 1916., p.165. (Box 17)
  - A Philosopher of Imagination. In the Nation (vol.103, no.2674).September 28, 1916., p.296. (Box 17)
  - The Philosophy of Religion. A review of The World and the Individual. In the Outlook (vol.66, no.8).October 20, 1900., p.466. (Box 17)
  - Memorials of Professor Royce. In the Harvard Alumni Bulletin (vol.19, no.14).January 4, 1917., p.261. (Box 17)
  - Some Modern Philosophy. A review of The Conception of Immortality. In the Outlook (vol.66, no.4).September 22, 1900., p.227. (Box 17)
  - Roycian Reminiscences; Letters to the Bulletin. In the Harvard Alumni Bulletin (vol.19, no.6).October 26, 1916., p.81. (Box 17)
  - The Teachings of Royce: an Estimation. In the California Alumni Fortnightly (vol.9, no.14).September 30, 1916., Loewenberg, J.; p.216. (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce: Interpreter of American Problems. Reprinted from the University of California Chronicle (vol.19, no.1)., Loewenberg, J. (Box 17)
  - The Philosophy of Religion. Review of The World and the Individual. In the Outlook (vol.71, no.8).June 21, 1902., p.511. (Box 17)
  - Un Pensatore Americano: Josiah Royce. Milan.1917., Ogliati, Francesco (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce: a Personal Impression. In the International Journal of Ethics (vol.27, no.2).January 1917., Mead, George H.; p.168. (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce. In the Harvard Graduates' Magazine (vol.25, no.98).December 1916., Palmer, George Herbert; p.165. (Box 17)
  - Josiah Royce. In the Outlook (vol.121, no.3).January 15, 1919., Slattery, Charles Lewis; p.114. (Box 17)
- Reviews of Royce's Books
  - The World and the Individual. Review of the Gifford lectures of the same title. In the Dial (vol.32, no.377).March 1, 1902., Caldwell, William; p.148. (Box 18)
  - Royce's The Problem of Christianity. Review in the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods. vol.11, no.22).October 22, 1914., Brown, William Adams; p.608. (Box 18)
  - Review of William James and Other Essays... In the Philosophical Review (vol.21, no.4).July 1912., Creighton, J.E.; p.478. (Box 18)
  - Studies of Good and Evil. Review in the Philosophical Review (vol.8, no.1).January 1899., Creighton, J.E.; p.66. (Box 18)
  - The World and the Individual. Review in the American Journal of Psychology (vol.11, no.4).July 1900., Colvin, S.S.; p.596. (Box 18)
  - Herbert Spencer. Review in the Psychological Bulletin (vol.2, no.6).June 15, 1905., Griffin, Edward H.; p.205. (Box 18)
  - The World and the Individual. Review in the Philosophical Review (vol.9, no.3).May 1900., Dewey, John; p.311. (Box 18)
  - The World and the Individual (vol.II.Nature, Man, and the Moral Order. Review in the Philosophical Review (vol.11, no.4).July 1902., Dewey, John; p.392. (Box 18)
  - The Relation of the Principles of Logic to the Foundations of Geometry. Review in the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods (vol.3, no.13).June 21, 1906., de Laguna, Theodore; p.357. (Box 18)
  - The Spirit of Modern Philosophy. Review in the Philosophical Review (vol.1, no.3).May 1892., Creighton, J.E.; p.322. (Box 18)
  - The Christian Doctrine of Life. Review in the Harvard Theological Review (vol.7, no.1).January 1914., Hocking, William Ernest; p.107. (Box 18)
  - Jahresbericht über Erscheinungen der anglo-amerikanischen Litteratur aus der Zeit von 1891-1892.Zeitschrift für Philosophie und philosophische Kritik (vol.104, no.1).1894., Jodl, Friedrich; p.117. (Box 19)
  - The Philosophy of Loyalty. Review in the International Journal of Ethics (vol.19, no.4).July 1909., Muzzey, David Saville; p.509. (Box 19)
  - The Sources of Religious Insight. In the International Journal of Ethics (vol.23, no.1).October 1912., Loewenberg, J.; p.85. (Box 19)
  - Race Questions and other American Problems. Review in the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods (vol.6, no.6).March 18, 1909., Rieber, C.H.; p.163. (Box 19)
  - Professor Royce's Refutation of Realism and Pluralism. Review of The World and the Individual in the Monist (vol.12, no.3).April 1902., Perry, Ralph Barton; p.446. (Box 19)
  - The Philosophy of Loyalty. Review in the American Journal of Psychology (vol.19, no.3).July 1908., Tanner, Amy E.; p.409. (Box 19)
  - Race Questions, Provincialism, and other American Problems. Review in the American Journal of Psychology (vol.20, no.4).October 1909., Riley, J.; p.588. (Box 19)
  - The Problem of Christianity. Review in the Hibbert Journal (vol.12, no.1).October 1913., Jacks, L.P.; p.215. (Box 19)
  - The Philosophy of Loyalty. Review in Zeitschrift für Philosophie und philosophische Kritik (vol.139, no.2).1910., Jacoby, Gunther; p.242. (Box 19)
  - William James and Other Essays in the Philosophy of Life. Review in the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods (vol.9, no.20).September 26, 1912., Kallen, H.M.; p.548. (Box 19)
  - The World and the Individual. Review of the Gifford lectures of the same title. In the Dial (vol.32, no.377).March 1, 1902., Caldwell, William; p.148. (Box 18)
  - Royce's The Problem of Christianity. Review in the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods (vol.11, no.22).October 22, 1914., Brown, William Adams; p.608. (Box 18)
  - Review of William James and other Essays... In the Philosophical Review (vol.21, no.4).July 1912., Creighton, J.E.; p.478. (Box 18)
  - Studies of Good and Evil. Review in the Philosophical Review (vol.8, no.1).January 1899., Creighton, J.E.; p.66. (Box 18)
  - The World and the Individual. Review in the American Journal of Psychology (vol.11, no.4).July 1900., Colvin, S.S.; p.596. (Box 18)
  - Herbert Spencer. Review in the Psychological Bulletin (vol.2, no.6).June 15, 1905., Griffin, Edward H.; p.205. (Box 18)
  - The World and the Individual. Review in the Philosophical Review (vol.9, no.3).May 1900., Dewey, John; p.311. (Box 18)
  - The World and the Individual (vol.2).Nature, Man, and the Moral Order. Review in the Philosophical Review (vol.11, no.4).July 1902., Dewey, John; p.392. (Box 18)
  - The Relation of the Principles of Logic to the Foundations of Geometry. Review in the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods (vol.3, no.13).June 21, 1906., de Laguna, Theodore; p.357. (Box 18)
  - The Spirit of Modern Philosophy. Review in the Philosophical Review (vol.1, no.3).May 1892., Creighton, J.E.; p.322. (Box 18)
  - The Christian Doctrine of Life. Review in the Harvard Theological Review (vol.7, no.1).January 1914., Hocking, William Ernest; p.107. (Box 18)
  - Jahresbericht über Erscheinungen der anglo-amerikanischen Litteratur aus der Zeit von 1891-1892.Zeitschrift für Philosophie und philosophische Kritik (vol.104, no.1).1894., Jodl, Friedrich; p.117. (Box 19)
  - The Philosophy of Loyalty. Review in the International Journal of Ethics (vol.19, no.4).July 1909., Muzzey, David Saville; p.509. (Box 19)
  - The Sources of Religious Insight. In the International Journal of Ethics (vol.23, no.1).October 1912., Loewenberg, J.; p.85. (Box 19)
  - Race Questions and other American Problems. Review in the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods (vol.6, no.6).March 18, 1909., Rieber, C.H.; p.163. (Box 19)
  - Professor Royce's Refutation of Realism and Pluralism. Review of The World and the Individual in the Monist (vol.12, no.3).April 1902., Perry, Ralph Barton; p.446. (Box 19)
  - The Philosophy of Loyalty. Review in the American Journal of Psychology (vol.19, no.3).July 1908., Tanner, Amy E.; p.409. (Box 19)
  - Race Questions, Provincialism, and other American Problems. Review in the American Journal of Psychology (vol.20, no.4).October 1909., Riley, J.; p.588. (Box 19)
  - The Problem of Christianity. Review in the Hibbert Journal (vol.12, no.1).October 1913., Jacks, L.P.; p.215. (Box 19)
  - The Philosophy of Loyalty. Review in Zeitschrift für Philosophie und philosophische Kritik (vol.139, no.2).1910., Jacoby, Gunther; p.242. (Box 19)
  - William James and Other Essays in the Philosophy of Life. Review in the Journal of Philosophy, Psychology, and Scientific Methods (vol.9, no.20).September 26, 1912., Kallen, H.M.; p.548. (Box 19)
- Reviews of Royce's Books; Essays in his Honor
  - Primer of Logical Analysis.... Review in Mind (no.26).April 1882., p.311. (Box 20)
  - Outlines of Psychology. Review in the Independent (vol.60, no.2858).September 10, 1903., p.2179. (Box 20)
  - The World and the Individual (vol.2. Review in Science (vol.15, no.374).February 28, 1902., Wenley, R.M.; p.347. (Box 20)
  - The Spirit of Modern Philosophy. Review in the Monist (vol.3, no.2).January 1893., p.306. (Box 20)
  - The Problem of Christianity. Review in the North American Review (vol.198, no.2).August 1913., p.282. (Box 20)
  - The World and the Individual. Review in the Nation (vol.70, no.1814).April 5, 1900., p.267. (Box 20)
  - The World and the Individual (vol.2). Review in the Nation (vol.75, no.1935).July 31, 1902., p.94. (Box 20)
  - Studies of Good and Evil; a Series of Essays... Review in the Nation (vol.67, no.1736).October 6, 1898., p.263. (Box 20)
  - Outlines of Psychology. Review in the Nation (vol.79, no.2048).September 29, 1904., p.264. (Box 20)
  - Papers in Honor of Josiah Royce on his Sixtieth Birthday [This volume appeared also as vol.25, no.3.May 1916 of the Philosophical Review]. (Box 20)
    Contains articles on Royce by John Dewey, etc.
  - Primer of Logical Analysis.... Review in Mind (no.26).April 1882., p.311. (Box 20)
  - Outlines of Psychology. Review in the Independent (vol.60, no.2858).September 10, 1903., p.2179. (Box 20)
  - The World and the Individual (vol.2. Review in Science (vol.15, no.374).February 28, 1902., Wenley, R.M.; p.347. (Box 20)
  - The Spirit of Modern Philosophy. Review in the Monist (vol.3, no.2).January 1893., p.306. (Box 20)
  - The Problem of Christianity. Review in the North American Review (vol.198, no.2).August 1913., p.282. (Box 20)
  - The World and the Individual. Review in the Nation (vol.70, no.1814).April 5, 1900., p.267. (Box 20)
  - The World and the Individual (vol.2). Review in the Nation (vol.75, no.1935).July 31, 1902., p.94. (Box 20)
  - Studies of Good and Evil; a Series of Essays... Review in the Nation (vol.67, no.1736).October 6, 1898., p.263. (Box 20)
  - Outlines of Psychology. Review in the Nation (vol.79, no.2048).September 29, 1904., p.264. (Box 20)
  - Papers in Honor of Josiah Royce on his Sixtieth Birthday [This volume appeared also as vol.25, no.3.May 1916) of the Philosophical Review]. (Box 20)
- Other Books
  - Human Psychology, by Judson Rea Butler and Theodore Francis Karwoski. New York and Chicago: Pitman Publishing Corporation.1936., Butler, Judson Rea (Box 7)
  - The Dresden Gallery. New York: Stroeffer and Kirchner.1875., Hübner, Julius (Box 7)
    Gift of Josiah Royce to his mother, 1876.
  - Essais. Paris, Fermin-Didot et Cie.1876., Montaigne, Michel de (Box 7)
    Gift from Josiah Royce to Anna Head, 1875.
  - The Poetical Works. Edited by Mrs. Shelly, with a memoir. Boston: Houghton, Osgood & Company.1878., Shelley, Percy Bysshe; 4 vol. in two. (Box 7)